JONATHAN LaPAGLIA: Previously...
SHONEE: I am here
because I want revenge.
..seven of Australia's
most notorious players...
Do we make a secret, solid alliance?
Yes.
..joined forces...
The King of the Jungle, the Golden
God, and the King of Bankstown.
We're the Power Bottoms.
(LAUGHS)
Come on! Let's go, Aussie!
..in an international battle...
Push it, push it! Go, go!
..where the highest honour
is up for grabs.
GEORGE: Nobody has been
a more powerful player than me.
(DAVID GRUNTS)
The Golden God is BACK!
David!
Wins immunity for Australia!
Aussie!
But to claim the title...
TONY: This season
is gonna be short and fast,
and that's my gameplay.
I'm fast and I'm furious.
..they will need to take out
seven of the world's best.
PARVATI: I've been playing this game
for decades.
For decades.
The three greats from the US...
CIRIE: Me and Parv rolled before.
This is not our first rodeo.
I would love to play this game
with you.
Oh!
..began with their backs
against the wall.
Rob launched his attack.
I know about you and David.
She was going to turn on us first.
But he misfired...
Rob.
..blowing up his own game.
13 are left.
Who will be going home tonight?
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
There has to be something.
You thought you could keep
the King of the Jungle
from playing against the world?
I'll see you soon.
Dreamin'!
Is it in here?
I would put it in here.
It's a fast-paced game.
But I always keep a few tricks
under my sleeve.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, nice.
So, yeah, OK.
Yeah, exactly. So...
Um...we don't know.
No.
It's getting pretty ripe.
Yes!
(LAUGHS)
Right...
Oh! (LAUGHS)
Not going hungry, bro.
Yes.
It's great to have Dave in the game.
And I know we're best buddies.
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
But I need to have eyes
in the back of my head,
because this game, you can get
stabbed from every single angle.
I can only trust myself.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. How crazy is that?
Oh!
(QUIETLY) Ahh! Ahh!
(LOUDLY) Ahh!
Look at that, baby!
Persistence pays off.
I've never played
a short game like this.
I want to get to the end,
and now I have this up my sleeve
for insurance the whole way through.
So this time,
I ain't telling no-one about this.
How good? How good?
Goddamn,
I'm the King of the Jungle, baby!
Don't ever forget it.
Huh!
He wanted
a unanimous vote yesterday.
Poor sweet blindsided baby Rob.
TONY: I'm still shocked.
Like, I don't believe
what he was doing, man.
That guy did not know when to keep
his mouth shut at tribal.
So, the way the tribe dynamic
is laid out now is so blurry to me,
so I can really see
that I have my work cut out for me
here in this tribe.
But everyone knows...
..the black widow is, like,
a dangerous female spider
who devours the men.
I might join you
because I haven't done that
since the first day.
I think it's time.
TOMMI: Going?
Yeah.
Oh, God.
Come to the water?
Yeah.
Maybe I gotta put a nice log
in there.
I'm best known on Survivor
for playing the fast
and the furious game,
but the last time I played Survivor,
I put myself in house arrest.
Quiet. You know?
Staying in camp, not running around.
It worked.
I won ¤2 million because of it.
And that's what I'm doing here too.
That's my strategy right now.
But once I get some traction,
I'm gonna be a runaway train.
(PARVATI, CIRIE AND KASS LAUGH)
Are they all in?
Yep, yep.
Huh?
Just taking a bath.
I hope so.
I didn't hear him say.
I still can't read any of them.
Like, Parvati never came to me
until she was ready to go home.
Me, Parvati and Cirie, we're
from America, we're Americans.
I would like to keep that strong.
But I've seen
Parvati and Cirie play.
They like the girl alliance.
We can bring together, like, a really
formidable women's alliance
because we are all so different.
KASS: Yes.
We can, like, get Lisa, 100%.
We can really make this happen.
Yeah. Totally.
I would love it.
(PARVATI, CIRIE AND KASS LAUGH)
If we were to lose a challenge,
what's going to happen?
What do you think's gonna happen?
Do you think they're gonna
go after one of us
and just keep it girl strong?
I don't know.
Now I'm nervous,
because if they don't care
about winning challenges,
they don't need to keep
strong people to help.
That's true.
That's what I'm nervous about now.
If Parvati and Cirie,
they turn their back on me
and they want me out, I'm gone.
(LAUGHS)
Nah.
DAVID: I am the biggest threat
in this game.
I'm such a big target,
you could throw an axe blindfolded
and hit me in the back.
Argh!
But right now I feel like
I'm sitting kinda pretty.
Like, I've got three
pretty solid friendships in here.
Really good to see you.
Yeah. It's so good to see you.
Ahh!
The only person I don't know at all
is Kirby.
And it seems to me like Kirby
could be someone I could manipulate.
Kirbs, did you rifle through
that fruit basket real good?
Like, made sure
there's definitely nothing
at the bottom of the fruit basket?
No.
OK.
When they walk out, this
is like a weed.
I'd like to have
real hair like this one day.
You sort of do.
(LAUGHS)
I'm working really hard on Kirby.
This is the girlest thing
I've ever done.
Yeah, I want to make her
feel like she can trust me.
(LAUGHS)
Because if we get five,
and with George and Shonee
on the outs,
I can have my way with this tribe
and really get off to
a roaring start.
Thoughts on today?
We're solid, right?
Whatever you think. Yeah.
We're solid?
Yep.
Right now, Shon's pretty quiet...
..and I don't think anyone
wants to work with George.
So, that's the two bottoms,
in my eyes.
What are you thinking?
I mean, exactly what you said.
I'm in amongst the kings and queens
and gods of the game.
And I'm just a princess
in this tribe,
so I'm playing my role,
and I love the fact that they think
that I don't know a lot.
But I... (LAUGHS)
I love that.
It's powerful.
If you go down that line...
No luck. Have you had any luck?
No.
I have looked and looked and looked.
Oh.
What do you mean?
(LAUGHS) Do you want to eat or not?
Oh, yeah. That thing.
Yes.
Would it not be David?
(GASPS) You can't say that
around people.
His network of spies
will turn on you.
I...
Strongest...
David...
Look, the easy option is Janine,
and we survive.
Then we can start getting exciting.
David, he's the Golden God
for a reason.
David has the charisma to pull
any player wherever he wants.
I like this a lot, Shon. Keep going.
(LAUGHS)
Tell me more, tell me more.
I'm very wary of people like that,
because I'M that.
Is David...
David's a shield for you?
Yes.
OK.
Dave would be way too early to take.
As soon as you take him,
it'd be like... I'd be, like...
Exposed?
Yes.
Are you open to...to, like...
Yeah.
Like, genuinely. Like...
I'd have to think...
I'd have to think about it.
Because he's a meat shield.
For who? You're all kings and
queens. What are you talking about?
It's wild because I don't think
they know how to say no to him.
That's the problem.
George is still on the cards,
but he's not going to win immunity.
SARAH: It's been seven years
since I played Survivor,
but in the Aussie tribe,
I've got a lot of strings to pull
when it comes to relationships.
Yeah, it's so nice.
I have known David for years.
Like, since I was 17 years old.
We know each other way back
from the modelling days.
We are close. We are friends.
What do you... What are you...
How do you like to play?
Like, we've never played together.
Yeah.
How do you like to play?
How do I like to play?
Well, the way I played first time
is not how I intend on playing
this time.
I didn't have, like,
a solid number one.
I love David as a friend,
but I don't want to get sucked up
into the supernova
that is the Golden God.
When I was playing season 2,
I was known for being a bit cheeky,
a bit sneaky.
I had many alliances, which
ultimately bit me in the bum.
I was unanimously voted off.
Yeah.
See, I'd rather...
This is the biggest game of Survivor
in the world.
Everyone has come to play.
There's kings, there's queens
and there's gods.
And I'm here to be the god slayer.
Come on in.
GEORGE: Ooh-ee!
LUKE: Oh, wow.
This is a very interesting-looking
challenge.
Aussies getting your first look
at the new World tribe.
Oh! Who...who went home?
Rob voted out
last night's tribal council.
(GASPS) Rob Bentele's gone!
No way.
Wow.
JANINE: Wow.
Good work.
Wow. Wowee, wow.
So, Parvati.
Interesting tribal last night.
It sure was.
What was the vibe like
when you got back to camp?
We were more unified
when we came back to camp,
and I think that was
really helpful for us.
So was it a 6-1 vote?
(LUKE CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Let's get down to the nitty gritty.
Just the look on Tony's face
said no.
JANINE: It wasn't unanimous? OK.
Tony doesn't want strength gone.
Tony could be working hard today.
KIRBY: Tony will be
working hard today.
I feel like girl power right now.
I'm...I'm feeling strong.
(LAUGHTER)
Tony's here, so he's happy.
Yes, sir.
Fascinating.
OK. Shall we get on with
today's immunity challenge?
CONTESTANTS: Yeah.
Come on, David.
Oh, you want that back, huh?
Want it back?
I'll get it back.
(CHUCKLES) OK, you'll get it back.
Alright.
Once again, immunity
is back up for grabs.
This is a pretty physical challenge.
You're going to use a heavy battering
ram to smash through a wall,
pass through a keyhole...
..transport blocks across a bridge
up onto a high shelf.
Once you have your blocks
in position,
you'll then attempt to
knock them down with sandbags.
First tribe to get it done
wins immunity
and is safe from the vote.
Losers, Tribal Council,
where somebody is going to become
the second person voted out.
Aussies, you've got an extra player.
You're gonna need to sit someone out.
Who's it going to be?
I'll do it.
I nominate.
Alright.
Shonee, you're on the bench.
Everyone else, minute to strategise.
Let's get this thing rolling.
Let's go!
Alright, here we go.
For immunity.
Come on, Aussies.
Survivors ready?
Go!
First thing you got to do
is untie that battering ram.
Right here. Right here.
Twist it, twist it, twist it.
Everyone working away
at those knots.
Right, we're clear.
Ready?
Three, two, one. Let's go.
Come on, guys, come on,
come on, come on, guys.
Both tribes
have their battering rams.
Moving on to the wall.
Need to knock out
every single brick.
TONY: We're starting with
the bottom left.
Come on. Ready?
Go, go.
That's good strategy.
World using their brains.
CIRIE: Get the bottom.
Get the bottom.
Wasting no time on their wall.
Just tip it. Just tip it.
Aussies are all over the place
right now.
That's it. Come on, guys.
World almost there.
Come on, sweep!
Couple more blocks will do it.
There it is.
Go the other side.
Go on the other side.
Slide your battering ram through.
DAVID: They're through.
Come on, guys!
Oh! There it is. There it is.
One more, one more. Go!
TONY: Go, Tommi. Go, Tommi.
Nice. Come on.
World tribe moving on to the keyhole.
Alright, go on the other side.
So, up this. Up.
Now you need to rotate it
back and forth
to get those handles
through the slot.
Nice and slow, guys.
Nice and slow. Hold on.
(DAVID GRUNTS WITH EFFORT)
One more, one more.
(GRUNTS)
Just one more in the middle.
Here we go, here we go. Here we go.
Finally, Aussies smash through
their wall. They're moving on.
Let's go, Australia! Let's go.
Let's go, Lukey.
Aussies moving on to the keyhole.
Wind it up, wind it up.
Lift, lift, lift.
Yeah! One more, one more!
World almost through.
PARVATI: Turn it, turn it.
Flip it over again.
TONY: Watch your feet,
watch your feet.
You're good! Move on, World.
Slow and steady here.
World have it done.
Slow down, guys. We need to rest.
We need to rest.
Alright, now you need to
clip on your carry handles.
Alright, these clips.
Start balancing your blocks
on that beam.
Get the first one balanced.
Yeah.
Yeah, keep it coming.
One more.
Finally, Aussies have their
battering ram through the keyhole.
They're moving on.
KASS: We feel it first.
TONY: Don't look at them.
Who cares? Right.
World still have the lead.
PARVATI: Slow and steady.
Let's just lift it up here.
Here comes the tricky part.
Now you need to carry all 12 blocks
across that bridge
without dropping any.
Nice and slow.
You drop a block...
Oh, no, no, no.
Shh, shh. Just keep it, keep it.
..you're gonna need to come
all the way back and start again.
Nice and slow.
Lift up the front a little bit.
Wait, wait. No, no, don't.
Don't lift.
We're good.
OK, guys. That's it.
You're good, World! That's good.
Move on.
Aussies going across the bridge.
Moving quickly now.
DAVID: Slow, slow. Slow down.
LUKE: Slow down. Slow down.
Slow. We're going too quick.
Why are we going so quick?
They drop a couple of blocks.
You need to come all the way back.
It's alright, it's alright.
Reset. Reset. Reset.
TONY: Alright, we're gonna go up
at an angle.
Meanwhile, World is slotting their
battering ram into position.
There it is!
Now the battering ram
becomes a ladder.
Now we go up.
Tommi going up now.
Nice and slow, guys. Nice and slow.
CIRIE: Come on, Tommi.
Tony tossing in the blocks.
Pass me the blocks. Here.
You need to get all your blocks
up on that shelf
before you can start
knocking them off.
Make it flush or it's gonna be
hard for us to push it off.
Push it flush, man.
Meanwhile, Australia almost across.
DAVID: Keep coming,
keep coming, keep coming.
Keep coming, keep coming,
keep coming. We're there.
There you are! You're good.
You're good, Australia.
Come on, let's go, let's go!
Unclip, Kirbs. Unclip, Kirbs.
TONY: One more.
World down to their last block.
There it is.
Come on, guys.
Oh!
Whoa!
It's all good.
CIRIE: Tommi, jump!
Run!
Now you can start throwing sandbags.
Go, Tony! You got this.
Oh, shit.
Come on, Tony!
Tony firing away.
So close! You got this.
You got this.
Oh, shit.
Come on, Tony!
Damn.
PARVATI: Come on, Tony.
Focus right on that bird's face.
Nail it.
Yeah!
Yes, Tony!
Tony takes out one block for World.
TOMMI: You got this. You got this.
And another one for World.
DAVID: Up, up, up, up!
Aussies scrambling to catch up.
Drive it!
GEORGE: Move, Sarah, move.
Oh, shit.
Come on, Tony.
I'm outta...
Take your time. Take your time.
CIRIE: Just focus.
Get ready, get ready, Tommi.
Tony getting tired out there.
You want to switch?
Yeah, yeah.
OK, switch out.
Tommi subbing in for World now.
Come on, Tommi!
Yes! Tommi!
Tommi connects.
(WORLD TEAM CHEERS)
And another one for World.
Go, Tommi!
Come on.
OK, come on. We got this.
One more. One more, Lukey.
Go.
Finally, Australia
gets all their blocks up.
DAVID: We're back in this.
Come on, Australia.
You need to pick this up.
Come on, come on.
David connects.
GEORGE: Come on, GG!
Hit it!
Yes!
Well done, Dave.
And another one.
Go, GG!
Golden God, up against
the best-ever winner.
Tony's back in for World.
CIRIE: Just like that.
Yes! Right there!
PARVATI: Come on, Tony.
Come on. Tony.
(CHEERS)
Tony clips another one.
Luke's in for Australia.
Yes, Luke!
He gets one.
Get it! Yes!
And another one for Luke.
DAVID: Go, Lukey. Keep it going.
Keep it going.
Boom! Yes, Luke!
And Luke again!
Aussies were so far behind
in this challenge,
but they've almost closed the gap.
Yes, Luke. Yes, yes!
Just as I say that...
Get it in there!
Wow!
Five left for the Aussies.
Five for World.
CIRIE: Yes!
PARVATI: Come on, Tony.
(CHEERING)
Just like that, three left for World.
GEORGE: Throw it!
Yeah!
Four left for Australia.
Yes. Yes!
Tony gets another one.
Down to the final two for World.
You got it.
You got this.
Come on!
World down to their final block!
(AUSSIE TEAM CHEERS)
Three left for Australia.
DAVID: Come on, Luke.
(CHEERING)
Yes, Luke!
Aussies down to two.
World down to one.
Tony going for the win.
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Oh, shit.
CIRIE: Take your time. You got it.
DAVID: Keep it going, Toki!
Get it! Oh...
(BLEEP)
This is it, Tony! Right here!
Right here for the World, Tony.
And he does it!
(ALL CHEER)
World wins immunity,
sending Australia to Tribal Council.
(ALL CONTINUE CHEERING, LAUGHING)
World, nicely done.
Immunity is yours.
Tony, get up here.
(LAUGHS)
One, two, three.
ALL: World!
Alright, World, you are safe.
Nobody going home.
Grab your gear. Head on out.
Enjoy your night off.
See you.
Bye.
Enjoy.
Have fun hanging out with Jonathan.
Nicely done.
Alright, Australia,
Tribal Council tonight,
where one of you will become
the second person voted out.
Head back to camp.
I'll see you tonight.
SHONEE: See you then.
Very sad thing to say, Jonathan.
(LAUGHS)
See you tonight.
First Tribal Council
for the Australia tribe.
I feel like they want a big head
for the first boot.
So, let's just get rid of George.
Easy peasy, bingo bango.
DAVID: Let's just
get this party started.
Bring it on.
Big ol' bottle of tequila. Let's go.
Let's find
where this tribe really sits.
Kirby and I,
we have this little thing going.
I think she might be keen
to play with me
and just see how...
how deep we can go.
If she really wants
to prove something,
that's what she should do.
I had a think about
what you said this morning.
What do you think about it?
Like, what do you want,
what do I want?
Mm-hm.
And 100%
I just want to be your number one.
You gotta look at me when you say it.
Yeah.
I'm good. I'm good.
Cool.
You just tell me a name.
I'm taking what you say
word as bond.
Yeah.
Then here's what I think
we should do.
George is a problem for me.
(MIMICS GEORGE)
The King of Bankstown.
You know, like, the king.
The kings always get their big head
and then they don't worry about God
no more.
I've needed to basically
bend to the knee
and go, "Golden God,
please accept my good wishes."
Yeah.
You know?
George needs to go right now.
Surely George, eh? Surely. I mean...
Well, safe vote is we split.
If we're a solid five
and we can pull Sarah,
we've got a 3-2.
KIRBY: Mm.
Or I just tell you guys what to do
and then you go and
(BLEEP) blindside me.
(LAUGHS)
Mm. Yeah.
JANINE: Or there's that option.
Yeah, yeah.
Please don't do that option.
(LAUGHS)
When you have the connections,
you can play with the numbers.
George doesn't have that.
David does.
So David's the one that has to go.
The only person that I've made any
kind of commitment to at the moment
is Kirby.
OK.
I've been planting the seeds
in everyone's heads about David.
And right now,
Sarah's putting her trust into me.
I've got Shonee
in this secret relationship.
And George, he'd be the vote out
if he doesn't come with us.
Kirby. Kirbs.
So, hopefully it's worked out.
So let's...let's pick someone.
If I'm gonna say the obvious...
Does it start with a D?
..there's a...
That's the big option.
That's the scary option
that could have big ramifications.
Safer option would be...
No, no. Go the big one.
Lay it out.
The big one is David.
Do we gamble and risk having
something blow up in our face
if it's David?
Yes.
Yes?
Yes. Why not?
We're only here once.
Life is for living.
Yes. Life is for living.
I don't need convincing.
GEORGE: First Tribal Council
for the Aussie tribe
and David the Golden God's name
came up.
If the Golden God goes home,
fantastic for my game.
But I have to be careful.
If people have a choice of voting
out the Golden God or King George,
they might just go for me.
And that's what worries me.
If you've got an idol,
you might need it.
Oh, I wish.
Yeah, I feel like that too.
Yeah. So, your name
has been thrown out.
I'm in the Power Bottoms alliance
with David, myself and Luke,
so I have to use one of
the most basic Survivor strategies -
"As long as it's not me".
Your destiny in this game
might come down to...
I'm doing this to save you.
I could have kept my mouth shut.
No, no, no. And it stays...
it stays here.
Yeah. So, it's like...we agreed
to look out for each other.
That's how you build trust, David.
Mm.
I don't trust George
as far as I can throw him,
which I'm guessing is about
20-ish metres, maybe 25,
depending on if I've eaten or not.
But it's definitely made me
a little bit worried.
SARAH: Nah, I'm going to stay here.
I don't want to be seen to be,
like, shifty.
Yeah.
(LAUGHS)
So, what you want to do
on this first vote,
I want to go with,
just to prove that...
..we're good.
Yeah, yeah.
Tonight's vote is about doing
what I said I'm going to do
and proving that I'm
a trustworthy alliance member.
I'm going to really keep it chill.
Like, I'm not gonna do
any cross-talking today.
Like I said, I want to, like,
prove my loyalties.
First time around I played,
I was a bit shifty.
I just want to, like,
make it abundantly clear.
Like, I feel like
she's famous for lying.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah. I'm the trickster.
And I'm like, "Hmm..."
Yes.
But I also want to
keep Dave in this game.
I know Dave. I have
a relationship with Dave.
I can read Dave.
Um...you need to pass on to David,
because I cannot be seen
to be talking to him,
that his name is absolutely,
um, the majority.
Yep.
Um, if he has an idol,
he needs to play it.
Yep.
There's nothing I can do
at this stage because...
..because of my alliance with Kirby.
Yeah.
So it's Shonee, Kirby...
George and you?
Yeah.
This is my solid as a friend.
No, no, no. Right.
I don't have it.
This...
Mm.
I thought we had
a really easy first vote -
take out George or Shonee
and really get off to
a roaring start.
But... Ugh!
I have a feeling that Kirby
and Shonee and George and Sarah
are getting together
to take my head off.
Rude!
I need to find out
who is really out to get me.
And your move, your first big move.
Mine? Ours.
Ours. Yeah, but...
Have you said any names to them?
Have they asked you for names?
That's their plan.
Like, David and Janine.
No. I'm gone.
I'm going home tonight.
No, you're not.
Yep.
You're not.
Yes, I am.
So, yeah.
Mm.
Oh, very good. Yeah.
Very good. We're about to wrap up.
But what have you been telling?
Because I got told there's a 3-2
George-Shonee split happening.
It's very disappointing.
All I'm hearing is it's fully on me,
from people I actually,
like, really trust.
Mm.
Um...
With what we discussed before.
Really?
Unless you change it. Yeah.
It's not what I'm hearing, George.
Mm.
She's right here.
Yeah.
How can he do that?
OK.
Yeah.
Alright. You guys do your thing.
No problem.
I am pissed.
How dare you throw my game
under the bus?
It's not just your game
that you need to consider.
You know you could have just said,
"It's no-one here."
Just so you know.
Yeah. It doesn't matter.
No, it does,
because it's also my game.
Mm. Mm.
No?
Let's vote him out tonight.
I am ready to vote David,
but George doesn't care about
anyone's game but himself.
Yeah,
but that didn't need to be said.
Mm.
Maybe it IS George that needs to go.
All good.
How's it?
Yeah. It's bad. It's me.
It's me.
Oh, my lord.
How's Kirby put herself
in that position?
Now she's, like, sitting in the water
and people walking up and...
She always has. The whole time.
She's a machine.
Now Kirby's sitting in the water.
The princess having a bubble bath.
Yeah, yeah.
I, the Golden God, have to walk down
to the water's edge?
Sit, sit, sit, sit.
So humiliating!
(GROWLS FRUSTRATEDLY)
So, the problem is,
is, like, I've got people telling me
you're driving a vote on me.
I'm not driving any vote on you.
Are you going to vote on me?
So, when I... No.
I'm solid.
But at this stage of the game,
I think it would be
so much better to get George out.
Listen to my strategy, please,
Kirby. Please! I'm begging you.
I'm not above begging. I'll beg.
I'll get down on my knees.
I feel like the convincing argument
is, one, I will get us through
a bunch of these things.
We've got two more at least.
Yeah.
Like, do you want George
lifting up stuff like that
and pushing it through the thing?
(LAUGHS) No.
You know? I'll be a much bigger
target than George at merge.
Yeah.
Much bigger. Like, let's go.
Like, I'm serious about what we said.
Yeah.
You know?
But I...I can't get through
myself tonight.
Yeah.
Like, I'm down. Like, let's roll.
Like, I really need you today.
I have a bad feeling it might be time
to start praying to the real God,
because the Golden one
might be in big trouble today.
What did Kirby say?
She's like, "I'm..."
No, she's 100% not with you.
Yeah, no, I know.
She...
I think she's the instigator of it,
to be honest.
I think so too.
So whatever she's saying,
I wouldn't believe her.
So maybe we go... We need Sarah.
To get around Kirby,
I need to pull in Sarah.
But she's being very stand-offish.
Yeah, I know. I know.
I'm at a crossroads
with how I played the last time
versus how I play this time,
and this vote could set me up as
the flip-floppy player or not.
So don't flip-flop. Just stay.
I'm like, "Well,
be loyal to me, then.
"Like, WE can play. Come on, girl.
"Like, I actually know you."
I have to vote with Kirby tonight
to prove...
Girl, if you don't play with me
tonight, I go home.
So, I'll tell you the only way
I can NOT go with
what Kirbs and Shon are doing.
OK.
Is convince Kirby that it should be
George that goes, not you.
It is absolutely mission critical
that I do what I say I'm going to do
come this vote.
But it bodes well for my long-term
plans to keep Dave in the game.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah?
So, um, I chatted to Dave,
because essentially all they'll need
for Dave not to go home,
all they'll need is one of us to
flip and go, um...and vote George.
Is it George's way or the highway?
Is that how he plays?
If George doesn't get
what he wants out of you,
he'll go around you.
And like I said, this is...
I'm cool to go with whatever,
because like I said,
you're my number one priority.
Yeah, well, let's do that, then.
Yeah.
OK?
Let's do it.
Alright.
Yeah.
Yeah?
Let's go George?
Let's do it.
Alright.
Um, so we're doing George, right?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Kirby doesn't want to have
that conversation,
so I feel like
if she stays quiet right now,
we just stick with
that original thing.
Yeah?
She's not voting George.
No. So, yeah. They're going for you.
She's voting you.
No, no, look, look. It's switched.
It's switched.
OK.
Yeah. Yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah. See? That's good. It works.
So, I gotta go.
Yeah. OK.
It's short.
OK.
Don't talk to anyone. That's good.
Hope that's... But that's...
OK.
Yeah.
Trust you.
OK.
You're, like, the one
that I actually am...legit trust.
Yes?
Shonee's talking to Kirby right now.
Someone's got to go and get in
on that Shonee conversation.
They want George.
Really?
They want all on George.
OK.
GEORGE: The longer this scramble has
gone, the more worried I'm getting,
because all I hear
is myself coming up as an option.
So, I need to make sure
that somebody who isn't King George
of Bankstown goes home.
What do you guys think?
Come in, Luke.
What would make you happy, Luke?
Honestly.
If Janine goes,
does that make you happy?
Uh...
Mm-hm.
Um...
If youse want to vote J,
I'll vote J.
We all just dump on Janine.
I'm taking control of the situation.
Vote off Janine and there's no
crying over spilt milk.
Janine goes home.
Is that a problem for you?
No, that's not a problem for me.
Is that OK for you?
Am I reinventing the wheel
with an "anyone but me" strategy? No.
But I've made sure I'm not
the first boot on this tribe.
Fine.
Always bet on black.
Or gold.
Go ahead. Grab a torch.
Come forward, dip it in and get fire.
GEORGE: Doing this again.
It's part of the ritual
of Tribal Council,
because in this game,
fire represents your life.
Once it's gone...
..so are you.
So, George, what do you think?
Do you like
what we've done with the place?
It seems familiar,
but different at the same time.
But given I come to Tribal Council
so often,
I was hoping for two nights off
in a row.
But that never happens for me,
does it?
Kirby, your season,
you had a lot of chaos,
so you should be at home right here.
Yeah... Oh, I feel like
that's just amateur league
in comparison to this.
They're professionals in every way,
and I feel like I'm amongst
kings, queens and gods,
and I'm the princess
amongst them all.
So...
OK. (LAUGHS)
Like, they're elite at this game,
and I love watching them
do what they do,
and they're so charming
and sweet and embracing,
and you just think, "Yes,
I'm with you, I trust you,"
and then you think about it
and you're like, "What...
"What were they just saying?"
So, they're really good.
Uh...Kirbs, I don't think
you should be
retracting yourself
from the same hill
because you were playing pretty big
today, in my opinion,
and I think you play this game
very, very well.
So to try and take yourself
out of the equation...
I'm still the princess.
I actually think Kirby is playing
one of the best games.
The way she's playing is...
like, it's amazing.
Not rattled at all. Super calm.
People coming to chat.
Like, people are looking to her
for what's going to happen tonight.
George, there are a lot of
connections in this tribe.
It's almost like a Venn diagram
of who's played with who, right?
Yeah. It's a...it's a tribe
with an interesting dynamic.
And I feel like the problem
that this tribe has had
after three days
of seven Australian legends together
is we have competing priorities,
and how you balance those
priorities, um...
(GEORGE CONTINUES TALKING,
AUDIO MUTED)
..you've got to take into account
in a couple of days we merge,
and then we're at endgame.
Wow. David, that...that was a lot.
Wait, what?
(OTHERS LAUGH)
Did you...did you hear any of that?
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES
IN BACKGROUND)
Janine, is that how fast
the game is now?
JANINE: Oh, yeah. It's...it's like,
um, Survivor on steroids.
It was like "bang!" into it,
and it's like, "Whoa." (LAUGHS)
So, Sarah, it's been like
seven years since you last played.
Yeah.
How different does this feel?
Yeah, you definitely feel like
you're playing with professionals
when you're playing Aus v World.
Like, it's straight into it.
But I'm trying a new tactic.
I was a little bit cheeky sneaky
last time I played.
I'm trying to go with
this loyalty thing.
See how it works for me.
Luke, do you feel like
it's any different for you?
Uh, no, not really.
I think it's like riding a bike.
I think we still lie and cheat
and steal, really.
It's the same game, but, uh,
maybe a little bit faster, this one.
I think we're going to experience
that throughout this whole game.
(LUKE CONTINUES TALKING,
AUDIO FADES)
There was names getting
thrown around at the start,
and then it changed again.
Um, it's seriously...
Like, look at it right now.
It's a live tribal.
Things can change here.
Right here. Like...
So, whatever happens at the beach
probably means nothing,
because what's gonna
happen here is...
..is going to change again.
There certainly is
a lot of whispering going on
down that end of the tribe.
In fairness, we kind of went, "Aaah!
Right, what's going on?"
So, Janine, are things changing?
Mate, it's frickin' Survivor,
isn't it?
So, you know, I...I get...
..I get awfully confused
about what's going on.
It's the first Tribal,
and no-one knows
where everyone really sits.
You know, we've had conversations,
we've had certain things.
You...you go talk, then. Go talk.
(LAUGHS)
Like, if you're down...
Yeah. OK.
That seems like...
OK.
So, Kirby, there was a clear split
in the discussions...
..right there.
Does that... Is that indicative of
what's going on in the tribe
in terms of alliances?
Don't ask me. The Kings and God
just went and spoke,
and I don't know what about
because they've been at each other.
I don't know - I think it's always
good to keep your options open.
And there's one thing to be,
like, hiding on the beach
or scurrying around the beach is...
(DAVID CONTINUES TALKING,
AUDIO FADES)
So how many conversations
were you part of this afternoon?
A lot.
I think a lot of names
got floated today,
so that makes people nervous.
I know my name
was getting floated today
and that made me very nervous.
Shonee, given your experience
at Tribal Council,
you must have a sense of
where the vote's going tonight.
Honestly, like, coming in here
and just, like, looking around...
(SHONEE CONTINUES TALKING,
AUDIO FADES)
And I feel like I'm coming in and...
(AUDIO FADES)
..I've played with
two people before.
They both voted me off.
That's a great start.
But what I offer is a clean slate
to the others.
And also... (AUDIO FADES)
So, Luke,
what's tonight's vote about for you?
Ooh. That is a very good question.
Uh, as...as simple as to put it,
is about how I'm moving forward
and who I want to move forward with.
So...
Agreed.
Because inasmuch as this
is an individual game,
you sometimes do need people
to actually have your interests,
uh, to move forward.
That's how I like to play.
Definitely have your guys back
when you say you have their back.
I like it. It's a good answer.
Let's see who's got whose back.
It is time to vote.
David, you're up.
Oof.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'll go count the votes.
Alright. If anyone has an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
I'll read the votes.
First vote, Janine.
George.
Two votes George, one vote Janine.
That's three votes George,
one vote Janine.
David.
Three votes George,
two votes David,
one vote Janine.
One vote left.
David. We're tied.
Three votes George,
two votes David, one vote Janine.
One vote left.
David. We're tied.
Alright, we're gonna revote.
This is how it's going to work.
George and David,
you will not vote.
Everyone else, you can only
vote for George or David.
Sarah, you're up.
I'll go count the votes.
Alright, I'll read the votes.
First vote. David.
David. That's two votes David.
George.
Two votes David, one vote George.
George. We're tied.
Two votes David, two votes George.
One vote left.
Second person voted out
of Australia Versus The World,
David.
I haven't had that many votes
since I won.
What the heck?
OK.
(BOTH SPEAK INDISTINCTLY)
I'm gonna take my time with this,
because I think that's the last time
I ever play Australian Survivor.
So, congratulations.
You guys retired me.
Alright, David, the tribe has spoken.
Beautiful.
He needs a standing ovation.
It's the Golden God.
(OTHERS AGREE)
Alright. Thanks, guys.
See you, brother.
Golden God out.
Well, this tribe might be
full of relationships,
but shack up with the wrong people,
you might just find yourself dumped.
Grab your torches, head back to camp.
Goodnight.
GEORGE: Whew! That was close.
LUKE: Yeah, it was close.
Whew!
The race is on.
But who will open Pandora's box?
TONY: These girls have a plan,
and they don't want Tony
to throw a monkey wrench into it.
And in that box
is probably a monkey wrench.
And a growing pest problem...
George does have tendencies
that a cockroach has.
They're known to be
very hard to get rid of.
..gets out of control.
I'm bringing out
that bazooka from Bankstown.
100%, Luke.
Janine can get juiced.
Luke can get liquidated.
I'm vengeful King George.
Yeah, look, there's definitely
some solace in...
No, I don't really play, so I'm...
I'm sour, you know?
I don't take solace in nothing. I
wanted to stay in the game. (LAUGHS)
But is there an honour
to be bestowed upon,
like, the biggest threat
going out early?
Yeah, maybe.
I would have much preferred
to be still in there.
It was, like, really down to
what Sarah was going to do.
And...I don't know,
that was such a 50/50.
And her saying she wanted to play
a loyalty game, I was like, "Bleah!"
I don't know if she's watched
any of the newer seasons,
but people don't like that.
I don't like that!
David, I do not like this feeling,
but sometimes loyalty is blind.
We'll see how it works out.
For what's left of the Aussies,
I mean, buckle up,
because it's about to get rowdy.
There's only one king, baby,
and it's the King of the Jungle.
Captions by Red Bee Media